CURRICULUM VITAE

Francesca ZAMMIT - CUTAJAR

Born: 15th August 1964

Nationality: British and Maltese

Email: fmazc@yahoo.com

Mobile: Malta +356 9915 9915 and whatsapp

Profile

A broad scope of experience and skill sets – Administrator; TEFL teacher; Public relations executive, Stress counsellor; Nutrition and Mindful Eating consultations and presentations.

People skills expressed with confidence, diplomacy and transcultural awareness.

English mother tongue. French fluent.

Event management experience backed up by solid all-round organisation skills.

Administrative experience over a broad range of employment and technical categories.

Education

1970-1977 Lycee des Nations, Geneva, Switzerland;

La Chataigneraie, Founex, Switzerland.

1977-1982 St Christopher School, Letchworth, Herts, UK

8 O levels, 3 A levels

1983-1987 University of Sussex, U.K

BaHons French and African and Asian Studies (2:1)

2011-2013 University of Maryland College Park, U.S.A; University of Malta

MaTCouns, Masters in Transcultural Counselling

Merit (STEPS scholarship awarded)

Further Education

Nov. 1988 Institute of Linguists, London, U.K. Diploma in Translation (French

into English) with merit in Literature

1990-1992 ION, London, Diploma in Nutrition.

1999 Intensive course in teaching English as a foreign language, TEFL at

IELS, Malta. (60 hours)

2017 April. CELTA at NSTS Malta

2018 Nov. SEPTT Malta

2001-2002 ITEC Anatomy and Physiology and Massage

July 2012 MBSR

Mindfulness - Based Stress Reduction Programme

www.london-meditation.co.uk

MB-EAT

Mindfulness Based Eating Awareness Training

Certified to Teach

www.thecenterformindfuleating.org

Relevant Skills and Experience

Languages: Mother tongue: English;

Good French, raised in Switzerland;

Some German
Some Italian

Computer Skills MS Word 2010 Operating Systems

Excel, Power point, Audio typing.

Use of Word Press website management

Employment History

(By Role)

PUBLIC RELATIONS

Malta Aug 2009 - Aug 2010

Xara Palace Hotel Relais & Chateaux, Mdina

P.R. Executive (3/4 time)

Guest relations - queries and complaints

Website content management, search engine optimisation, translation of English website into French.

Organisation of Xara Palace contribution to "Medieval Mdina" yearly local event.

Budget, costumes, ordering, individual events.

Malta Sep 2010 - Sep 2011

Jesuit Refugee Service (JRS Malta)

Development Officer (¾ time)

Creation of new information leaflet for public awareness campaign (design, copy and printing); fund raising events organising, start to finish (art exhibition).

SECRETARY/ADMINISTRATOR

U.K. 87 – Mar 90 Temp. Secretary, London UK

U.K. Jan-June 2001 Temp Secretary, Brighton, East Sussex, UK

U.K. Feb 27 2015 - Oct 2015

Patient Experience Administrator at Secamb (South East Coast Ambulance). Processing incoming compliments to Secamb staff by way of liaising with staff and general public via email and telephone.

Use of Outlook, Datix, Excel.

Malta 1994 Temp Secretary

Malta 1994-1995 French Groups Assistant, Alpine Travel, Malta (full time)

Booking large groups into hotels and conference centres. Use of

French for computer and telephone liaison.

TRANSLATOR (English-French-English)

Brussels Mar 90 - Aug 91

Internship at the European Economic Community, Brussels, Department of Information Communication and Culture (DGX).

Translations and responsibility for video library of films on the developing world.

Secretarial duties at the NGO 'ZEBRA', Brussels, for the publication of a magazine in French and English on films and video productions on and by developing countries.

ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEACHER

Paris 85-86 English Language Assistant Lycee de Champigny, Paris, France

Malta 94, 95, 96,01,02,07

Part-time teaching English as a foreign language to teens and adults in language schools (A&M, IELS)

Palma de Mallorca

September - November 2017

TEFL teaching to under 15's at the *English Academy*.

June 2018 - Present 2019

TEFL teaching online to Chinese students with *Dadaabc*

COUNSELLOR (part-time)

April 2015 to now Self-employed Counsellor and Mindful Eating Coach – Home clinic –

one to one and group workshops.

Malta 2012-2014 Volunteer Counsellor at San Anton Senior School: 330 hours

Volunteer Counsellor at Dar Qalb Shelter for victims of domestic

violence (ages 10-15): 15 hours

Delivery of mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR) programmes for teens at San Anton private school and for adults at Lily Aguis

Gallery, Sliema.

Individual Counselling and Nutrition Consultations at

St James Hospital, Sliema.

Presentation of research on mindfulness used in counselling persons

Profession MACP/Dept of Counselling research conference, February

managing anxiety at the Malta Association for the Counselling

2014

Journalistic contributions for The Times of Malta and TASTE

Magazine (Editor Daphne Caruana Galizia)

NUTRITION CONSULTANT (NC) (part-time)

UK Jan 92 - Mar 93 Self-employed Nutrition Consultant. Home clinic and consultations

at the Rock Clinic, Brighton, UK.

Journalistic contributions.

Malta Mar 93 to 95 NC at the Athenaeum Health Center at the Corinthia Hotel.

Malta 95 – 2015 Private NC St James Hospital, Sliema.

NC for Good Earth Health Food Distributors, Malta. Created a

nutritional database.

Programme of nutrition education prepared and presented at Chiswick

Junior and St. Martin's Senior schools Malta over one year (2003).

Journalistic contributions for Elegance Magazine, Taste Magazine, Tune-In, Business Weekly, the Independent and the Times of Malta

Presentations - Chiswick House, St Martin's and San Anton, Malta.